Wuse II, Abuja, Nigeria +2347080475424 osememen.ogbe@gmail.com memencodes.netlify.app

Osememen Ogbe

Skills

Node JS

Express JS

PHP

Laravel

Go

React JS

Next JS

Vue JS

TailwindCSS

Vuetify

MySQL

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Git

Redis

Docker

Linux Operations

I am an innovative and proactive full-stack developer with 4-years of working experience building client-tailored performant web applications. My tech stack includes Node, Express, PHP, Laravel, Go, React, Next and Vue.

I look forward to the possibility of discussing how my skills and experience can benefit you or your team further to achieve your project goals.

Work History

EFNetwork [Full-stack Developer]

June 2023 till now

Project: **GabTaxi** a ride-hailing start-up (similar to Uber) that offers affordable and safe transport services across Nigeria.

- * The back-end is built using a microservice architecture with the API gateway and other services for handling drivers, passengers, ride requests and trips, payments, agents, reports and so on. The endpoints are consumed by the Flutter-powered driver and passenger mobile apps, and Vue frontend admin and agent web applications.
- * There is an extensive usage of Firebase realtime database and Pusher for handling push notifications for passenger ride requests, searching for available drivers, accepting/rejecting ride requests from drivers, getting trip status, etc.
- * Another important feature I've worked on involves geofencing for determining service locations and rejecting ride operations outside such defined areas.
- * Additional features include Paystack for handling card trip payments and driver wallet withdrawals and Agora for real-time calls and messaging when passengers request rides.

SiiTech [Full-stack Developer] (Remote)

January 2023 till now

Project: An e-Portal for **NEPZA** (Nigerian Export Processing Zones Authority) to oversee Free trade zone activities in Nigeria and a separate e-Portal for Free trade zones that do not have a proprietary software for processing registration and licensing requests for businesses that want to settle in their respective zones. Both web applications are inter-connected.

Below are some of the tasks I completed on this project:

- * Built the back-end using Laravel (with extensive usage of requests, guards, events, observers, jobs, repository pattern, etc).
- * Developed a well architected roles and permissions system for authorizing, appraising and approving multi-step applications for enterprises to get a spot in a Free trade zone in Nigeria and receive various licenses.
- * Integrated Remita for handling electronic payments for applications.
- * Built the in-house front-end of the Zones e-Portal using Vue 3 Composition API and TailwindCSS.
- * File storage with Amazon S3 buckets.
- * Email notifications using Mailables and Sendgrid.

Bex-IT Digital Solutions [Full-stack Developer]

September 2022 to December 2022

Project: **SavingsBox** is a web application that enables users access various loan, savings, investment and group contribution plans (quite similar to PiggyVest).

- * Worked in a team of 3 developers and built out the business logic of the savings module with Rest API endpoints using Node.js and MongoDB for data storage. Users can subscribe to various saving plans
- * Built an auto-savings system with the aid of the card authorization and recurring payment features offered by Flutterwave (an online payment processor) and task schedulers.

Live: https://savingsbox.ng

BigCommand LLC [Full-stack Developer] (Remote)

September 2021 to June 2022

Project: **Adilo** is an online video hosting, sharing and streaming platform.

- * Made contributions to the back-end built with Laravel by developing custom scripts to interact with third-party packages that offer video sharing features.
- * Converted UI/UX designs from Adobe XD into reusable front-end components using Vue.js and Element UI for the video recording module and utilized WebRTC for seamless video communication and collaboration.

Overall, developing Adilo was a valuable learning experience that helped me develop my full-stack development skills and gave me a deeper understanding of the video hosting and sharing space. I worked with a multi-national team and had the opportunity to contribute to a product that is used by businesses across the world.

Live: https://adilo.com

Reimnet [Full-stack Developer]

July 2020 to June 2021

Project: **Hire4Africa** is an online recruitment platform for financial and accounting professionals in Africa.

* Developed the back-end with Node.js and MongoDB and provided Rest API endpoints for the front-end developer such as for viewing available job postings, job filtering, applying for job, viewing best talent matches for recruiters, multi-package subscription system, in-app and email notifications, online payments via Paystack, etc.

Live: https://hire4africa.com

Project: **SuezElectric** is an online platform for purchasing electricity units.

- * I came onboard on this project to add a few features to an already live running Laravel and Vue.js application. This included a revised agent commission module, modifying the existing wallet system to include a bonus wallet and developing a new promotional service.
- * Integrated Providus Bank Virtual Payment Service APIs and webhooks for credit/debit card payments and bank transfers for users who want to buy electricity units..

SuezElectric services are currently in use by thousands of Nigerians and the company processes tens of millions of Naira worth of transactions annually.

Live: https://suezelectric.com

Hobby Projects

Workcation

A front-end highly-responsive vacation home-listing website built with Vue 3 and Tailwindcss.

Github: https://github.com/oseogbe/workcation

Link: https://oseogbe.github.io/workcation

Netflix Clone

A full-stack Netflix-clone project built using Next 13, React, TypeScript, Stripe, Firebase and TailwindCSS.

Github: https://github.com/oseogbe/netflix-clone

Link: https://netflix-clone-rho-mauve-31.vercel.app

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computing and Information Technologies

January 2019 to December 2020

University of Derby

Advanced Diploma: Professional Computing and Information Processing

April 2018 to December 2018

Institute of Commercial Management

National Diploma: Computer Software Engineering

February 2016 to March 2018

Aptech Computer Education